<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Kim Pham</title>
    <link>http://kimpham54.github.io/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Kim Pham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kimpham54.github.io/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>flatiron school portfolio project 004 &#43; church wafer javascript</title>
      <link>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/005/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/005/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my fourth portfolio project for flatiron while doing a west coast tour of the United States. inspired by my friends, ardent lovers of good food made with care and consideration, i decided to make my application about recipes. i find that the flatiron school has a solid, tight curriculum - everything i&amp;rsquo;ve learned in the program so far has built upon each other.
in a specific programming language (Ruby) you start by learning about basic programming (basic operators, syntax, loops), then learn about object-oriented programming, then you learn about HTML, CSS, SQL, then you learn a lightweight Ruby framework (Sinatra), then a more powerful Ruby framework (Rails), then using Ruby and Rails with vanilla (meaning basic, or church wafer) Javascript, and finally we&amp;rsquo;ll learn to use a powerful Javascript framework (React).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>flatiron school portfolio project 003 &#43; ruby on magic</title>
      <link>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/004/</guid>
      <description>i completed my first ever ruby on rails project - climbing_gear. that, for me, is a pretty big deal! for a long time i&amp;rsquo;ve used programming languages for scripting, adding simple functionality and building some pretty simple applications where i worked on just the frontend/backend/server. i never worked on each level of an application. so making a full stack rails application is something i&amp;rsquo;m pretty glad i got to finally do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>flatiron school portfolio project 002 &#43; making reading lists with sinatra</title>
      <link>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/003/</guid>
      <description>it was a quick turnaround for me to build our second portfolio project, a Sinatra app that uses a whole new slew of ruby web technologies for me, including Rack, Activerecord, Rake, and bcrypt.
in brief, i built an application that behaves like a content management system in that it lets people have their own account to create a list of items to read in the future. a user can add a reading item and enter in an item&amp;rsquo;s title, url, and notes about the reading item.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>flatiron school portfolio project 001 &#43; updating nokogiri</title>
      <link>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 22:42:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimpham54.github.io/post/002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;our cohort is is working on our first portfolio project two months into the flatiron school software engineering part time program. we were asked to create a ruby gem that provides a command line interface to interact with the application that uses an external data source (either by API or web scraping). we were able to use any external data source we wanted, so i made the obvious choice for myself and decided to scrape &lt;a href=&#34;https://mountainproject.com&#34;&gt;mountain project&lt;/a&gt;, a site that describes climbing routes and locations in north america.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i put the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kimpham54/classic_climbs_cli_gem&#34;&gt;classic climbs code repository&lt;/a&gt; up on github with details on how to install and run the application. it&amp;rsquo;s a little object oriented application that scrapes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mountainproject.com/area/classics?type=sport&#34;&gt;classic sport climbs&lt;/a&gt;, prints out a list of those climbs, and the user can then select one of those climbs to get more details about it, scraped from a specific climb&amp;rsquo;s page, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mountainproject.com/route/106183204/space-boyz&#34;&gt;space boyz&lt;/a&gt; (point of pride note: i climbed this route in march!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it was a fun exercise to create this application, and it helps that you get to work on content that you enjoy working with. getting to build an object oriented ruby application hardened some of the concepts for me, and helped me think through some of the ways to optimize the program by thinking hard about separation of concerns, improving performance, and trying to be DRY (don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i wanted to note one thing, which makes me think about what it means to work in tech or to be a software developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the tl;dr: software development is not just about programming and getting your code to work for you, there&amp;rsquo;s many considerations to take into account to say that you have a working application. it&amp;rsquo;s the planning, setting up environment, testing, deployment, security, everything to make your code not only work but continuously operational.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>