<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Kim Pham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Kim Pham</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>rustling in the open source maplibre community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &#xA;![caption](../../images/2022-10-01-001-sparql.png &#34;caption&#34;)&#xA;[text](https://www.url.com) --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;starting in september i spent a few months learning rust. i had a few inchoate reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to learn systems programming&amp;hellip;i wanted to be exposed to deeper programming concepts. i do appreciate web development and working on web and business logic on the front and backend, but i&amp;rsquo;m also interested in coding that&amp;rsquo;s closer to computer science, or at least working with the ideas of computer science. and to better understand things at a lower level. rip off the hood of abstraction&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;people talk about it a lot on hacker news and in the blockchain space, i know you know. but also&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;linux is supporting rust. cool! so i guess it&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s here to stay&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;so then i learned it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kimpham54/rust-book-homework-kim&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kimpham54/rust-book-homework-kim&lt;/a&gt;. i was pretty motivated because i was trying to get into the january polkadot blockchain academy in buenos aires, and got through most of the rust book. unfotunately i didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to take the rust exam&amp;hellip; so now what? well i really enjoyed learning it, so might as well put those amateur skills to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>title</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/2022-10-01-001-sparql.png&#34; alt=&#34;caption&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.url.com&#34;&gt;text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ontology coordination with sparql</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t it beautiful? it&amp;rsquo;s web3.0!&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/2022-10-01-001-sparql.png&#34; alt=&#34;ontology&#34; title=&#34;ontology&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(extensive amounts of CIDOC CRM usage not included in photo)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;my colleagues and i are working on building up the semantic web, that is, web 3.0, or linked data. you may be familiar with its blingy $$$$ counterpart web3, but web3.0 had the catchy name first point O!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but wait, what&amp;rsquo;s the difference? everything darling, web3.0 and web3 has some inklings of a shared decentralization mission, but the ecosystem is entirely different. the web3 is blockchain based and cares about trust. web3.0 cares about interoperability and wants to operate with an open world assumption. says the w3c:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>machine learning &#43; stable diffusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;on a sunday, some sundays ago, i took my quiet night as a cue to nerd up, so i downloaded stable diffusion and played around with it. i read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jonstokes.com/p/ai-content-generation-part-1-machine&#34;&gt;a beautifully written piece about machine learning by jon stokes&lt;/a&gt;, setting aside any political views, which was deeply moving and really made me want to play around with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the setup is simple, you (my non-existent reader) can use the colab notebook i pasted below, or to install it on your local, you can follow my already going to be outdated in october 2022 steps that i followed from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/levelsio&#34;&gt;@levelsio&lt;/a&gt; who followed that from someone else:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
