<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open source on Kim Pham</title>
    <link>https://kimpham54.github.io/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open source on Kim Pham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kimpham54.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>open source maps and rust</title>
      <link>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/012/</guid>
      <description>i spent a few months learning rust in the end of 2022 for a few half-formed reasons:
it was always a desire of mine to learn systems programming. i really want to get into some deeper programming, i do love the creative solutions that web development can provide at the frontend/backend level, but i&amp;rsquo;m also interested in computer science concepts and at least understanding the ideas of building for computer science, not just business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>title</title>
      <link>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/template/</guid>
      <description>text</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ontology coordination with sparql</title>
      <link>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/011/</guid>
      <description>isn&amp;rsquo;t it beautiful? it&amp;rsquo;s web3.0! (extensive amounts of CIDOC CRM usage not included in photo)
my colleagues and i are working on building up the semantic web, that is, web 3.0, or linked data. you may be familiar with its blingy $$$$ counterpart web3, but web3.0 had the catchy name first point O!
but wait, what&amp;rsquo;s the difference? everything darling, web3.0 and web3 has some inklings of a shared decentralization mission, but the ecosystem is entirely different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>machine learning &#43; stable diffusion</title>
      <link>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/post/010/</guid>
      <description>on a sunday, some sundays ago, i took my quiet night as a cue to nerd up, so i downloaded stable diffusion and played around with it. i read a beautifully written piece about machine learning by jon stokes, setting aside any political views, which was deeply moving and really made me want to play around with it.
the setup is simple, you (my non-existent reader) can use the colab notebook i pasted below, or to install it on your local, you can follow my already going to be outdated in october 2022 steps that i followed from @levelsio who followed that from someone else:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
