<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cvs on Kim Pham</title><link>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/</link><description>Recent content in Cvs on Kim Pham</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Presentations</title><link>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/presentations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/presentations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last updated in 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024 - IMPRS Digital Humanities Workshop: GIS in history. &lt;em&gt;Max Planck Institute for the History of Science.&lt;/em&gt; online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 - Collections as Data: Transcribing Medical Records. &lt;em&gt;UCSF Digital Health Humanities Symposium.&lt;/em&gt; online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 - On data interpretation. &lt;em&gt;Collections as Data: State of the Field and Future Directions.&lt;/em&gt; Vancouver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 - Blockchain in the Humanities. &lt;em&gt;DH2023.&lt;/em&gt; online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 - Which times matter to write history? Time as a causal factor. &lt;em&gt;GRAPHNR2023.&lt;/em&gt; online. &lt;a href="https://graphentechnologien.hypotheses.org/files/2023/05/GrapHNR-2023-22-Valleriani-Which-times-matter.pdf"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Building apps for digital humanities projects with vue.js. &lt;em&gt;European Library Automation Group.&lt;/em&gt; Riga, Latvia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Building a Central Knowledge Graph for Multiple Humanities Research Projects. &lt;em&gt;European Library Automation Group.&lt;/em&gt; Riga, Latvia. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H_E67LcgZmYjanRgTapLyHBPIuNW8J_7xZZ1K8STJZM/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Introduction to the Digital Research Infrastructure for the Humanities. &lt;em&gt;code4lib conference.&lt;/em&gt; Buffalo, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fUBQaYnL3vP3CVUZWcpPEh8ZUbto3BqbYmCBFn4uGa0/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Uncovering Health History: Transcribing, Publishing, and Protecting Archival Medical Records as Data: A Case Study Involving Records from the Jewish Consumptives’ Relief Society. &lt;em&gt;The Network of the National Library of Medicine.&lt;/em&gt; online. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1QnUax4Vfe64BVIApxEmHA3oF0eJqV6CI/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=109117385609990247149&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Using flowmaps to visualize epistemic networks. &lt;em&gt;Graphs and Networks in the Humanities.&lt;/em&gt; Amsterdam, Netherlands. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Og1fxrE7_45uCycMORcSQy62el_TrWtFS1hv_5SmkVw/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Building a Central Knowledge Graph for Multiple Humanities Research Projects. &lt;em&gt;Graphs and Networks in the Humanities.&lt;/em&gt; Amsterdam, Netherlands. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H_E67LcgZmYjanRgTapLyHBPIuNW8J_7xZZ1K8STJZM/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Tracing Innovation with Representation Learning in the Sphaera Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Graphs and Networks in the Humanities.&lt;/em&gt; Amsterdam, Netherlands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 - Development process for digital humanities projects. &lt;em&gt;Max Planck Institute for the History of Science.&lt;/em&gt; Berlin, Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 - Developing a Digital Research Infrastructure for the Digital Humanities. &lt;em&gt;ENCODE conference.&lt;/em&gt; Leuven, Belgium. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1dt2pY-uGYj8Y3Q4KbbuSgBaLkVlHzQ2mY9MPwZhbTQI/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 - Introduction to Digital Humanities. &lt;em&gt;Max Planck Institute for the History of Science.&lt;/em&gt; Berlin, Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 - Introduction to Blockchain for Digital Humanists. &lt;em&gt;CORDH.&lt;/em&gt; online. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1A_pcRVHjWM531-babCv23IsywYI9hF88wW2YUXkBdwk/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 - Mining the past for the future: Collections as data as an organizational model in a data-driven world. &lt;em&gt;ACRL.&lt;/em&gt; Seattle, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/18c1-KPJkuoDIixEVpc0iM8RwJtz7_2O5uj4f_Ca0d7Y/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 - Transcribing collections using Transkribus machine learning. &lt;em&gt;Transkribus workshop.&lt;/em&gt; Denver, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1n6SK36MBQ6u6HWXlADtAIyczr1EeK0Rg_2MlGZ2t7O8/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - Integrating Collections as Data into Digital Repositories. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Stellenbosch, South Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - Developing an API to access digital repository digital collections. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Stellenbosch, South Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - Library Carpentry Workshop. &lt;em&gt;Library Carpentry at Purdue University.&lt;/em&gt; online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - Vertical Collaboration in a Digital Collections Ecosystem. &lt;em&gt;Lighting the Way Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Stanford, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1gLioqbH1P3xN2ijyH5LW_C1yZT_DBYCFFe_ZdWQVJFg/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - 2020 Recap. &lt;em&gt;Collections as Data Summative Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Las Vegas, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1wp-_-idXsplHHfx80uv54FPdMm4Jo0Q1PFkOCtqZSHk/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Digitization projects with Transkribus. &lt;em&gt;code4lib Colorado.&lt;/em&gt; Denver, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Digital collections ecosystem project briefing. &lt;em&gt;DU IT Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Denver, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Collections as Data at the University of Denver. &lt;em&gt;LYRASIS summit.&lt;/em&gt; Chicago, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Handwritten Text Recognition on Historical Medical Records from the Jewish Consumptives’ Relief Society. &lt;em&gt;DH and the Visual World.&lt;/em&gt; Boulder, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s2p1SKUBeL8Umle0_k_PATldS1XTlxVcJxkF8WI7G5c/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Handwritten Text Recognition Technology and Digitization. &lt;em&gt;ASIST Techbyte.&lt;/em&gt; Denver, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10xM1RxbDE3hGZRBXseJmbEOQyxtKs9wjo_5HRuDo-rI/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - In a third space: Building a horizontally connected digital collections ecosystem. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Hamburg, Germany. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1UI1K6LbjuAYsbGPSMQaxaSXElUd-uud2g71Gv3TygaI/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Managing Digital Institutional Content: Repository Projects. &lt;em&gt;CNI.&lt;/em&gt; Washington DC, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Part to Whole Kickoff: Redefining Roles and Services to Support Collections as Data. &lt;em&gt;CNI.&lt;/em&gt; Washington DC, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/139h5c22IPD0ivkOntqlsFEo2frJtmwq51spXd59vxHo/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Handwritten Text Recognition and the Beck Archives. &lt;em&gt;DU AI Summit.&lt;/em&gt; Denver, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Alternative Digital Repositories. &lt;em&gt;LDCX.&lt;/em&gt; Stanford, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019 - Show us yer strength! The ways we flex ElasticSearch. &lt;em&gt;code4lib conference.&lt;/em&gt; San Jose, USA. &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jxwf92XSp6YOgyOVk3Kh2U9Bk_5L6j2l/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Admin track: Introducing Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Islandora Camp Halifax.&lt;/em&gt; Halifax, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Supporting Web Annotations in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Islandora Camp Halifax.&lt;/em&gt; Halifax, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Supporting Digital Scholarship in Islandora CLAW: Linked Data Modeling for Humanities Data. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Bozeman, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10M7NQuBGHM3l1FwSAdQqbfyTE-4Kg0xmiww9Ma2NxEw/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Working with the W3C Web Annotation Standards and Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Bozeman, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1C9Md6HJUvpllkJ-G3zGWrD_C8R-rFuWKEiQE4skr4x0/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Investing in open-source – community-level strategies for developing sustainable software. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Bozeman, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1UV0_eT3Swa49aCeYW4FvPcXPwB9I8aDzuYkg0GG6yK8/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Early notes from a repository early adopter. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Bozeman, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1UhFRDwW9K9731xGu2U0ZJ6RfRU-hoiSTKUN6mB_kzwE/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Recursive and Reflective Building of Digital Collections. &lt;em&gt;TRY Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/11tD2YpYUq7zv3v2fiakgLPd_2GcKIRnjdpDnd7LCTfk/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Supporting Digital Scholarship in Islandora CLAW: Linked Data in the Dragoman Renaissance Research Platform. &lt;em&gt;Islandora CLAW Event.&lt;/em&gt; online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Introduction to static site generators. &lt;em&gt;code4lib conference.&lt;/em&gt; Washington DC, USA. &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bRKSXF82a1k_-km_VrAVEuPr2EYddoM8/view?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 - Hands-on Islandora. &lt;em&gt;iSkills Workshop.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Introduction to Python for Scientific Computing. &lt;em&gt;University of Toronto Scarborough Physics Students Union.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Digital Scholarship Tools and Techniques. &lt;em&gt;Tamil Internet Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Let’s talk about digital repositories!. &lt;em&gt;code4lib Toronto.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Supporting Oral Histories in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Islandora Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Hamilton, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Introduction to the Web Annotation Utility Module. &lt;em&gt;Islandora Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Hamilton, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Workshop - Building static site generators for your personal projects. &lt;em&gt;code4lib North.&lt;/em&gt; Ottawa, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Web Annotation Framework in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;code4lib conference.&lt;/em&gt; Los Angeles, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1K9jbimHWK6RdY8gh_29aB1wAiyiRMWPpmoJACx_pBGQ/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Virtual Uncommons - Connecting Digital Liaisons: Technical skill sets in digital library settings (Twitter Panel). &lt;em&gt;ASIS&amp;amp;T SIG DL.&lt;/em&gt; online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Forming a Digital Scholarship Unit. &lt;em&gt;TechKnowFile.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Version Control with Git. &lt;em&gt;UTSC Graduate Professional Skills.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - CLDI IT Workshop. &lt;em&gt;CLDI Summit 2016.&lt;/em&gt; Montreal, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Managing development of MediaCAT, an open-source web crawler. &lt;em&gt;UTSC Library Conference Day.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Repository as Research Method: a Digital Collections Virtuous Circle. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Indianapolis, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1n_yXwB9fflHhPSwD9HywP9QQOnYGi98neXIc_Nxvj3E/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Zen and the art of repository maintenance. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Indianapolis, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H_E67LcgZmYjanRgTapLyHBPIuNW8J_7xZZ1K8STJZM/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Islandora in the Classroom: Digital History and Repositories. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Indianapolis, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Collaborating with your Computer Science Department. &lt;em&gt;code4lib North.&lt;/em&gt; Hamilton, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - #UTSCFinanceHacks: Planning and executing a successful student hackathon in 6 weeks. &lt;em&gt;TRY Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Getting your hands dirty with web scraping. &lt;em&gt;code4lib conference.&lt;/em&gt; Philadelphia, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Curate my web crawl with MediaCAT. &lt;em&gt;code4lib conference.&lt;/em&gt; Philadelphia, USA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1jgULVK2oVrusUZ_6s5yIxV1jxGrwqfwlZOo1a4cw3o8/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Image and Meme Analysis with Python: I know words and images. &lt;em&gt;Web Archives Unleashed.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Using Islandora to build digital collections. &lt;em&gt;OLA Superconference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Getting Started with Islandora Solr Views. &lt;em&gt;Collections UofT Meetup.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Web Mapping with Python and Leaflet. &lt;em&gt;Digital Pedagogy Institute.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - The Learning in Neural Circuits Research Environment: Managing Living Specimens and Laboratory Data in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Dublin, Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Developing Open Oral Histories in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Open Repositories.&lt;/em&gt; Dublin, Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Digital Humanities and Your Dissertation Workshop. &lt;em&gt;University of Toronto Scarborough Graduate Studies.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Digital Preservation and Experiential Learning in History HISD18. &lt;em&gt;CTL Teaching Showcase.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1sK7nejlxvTB2p6sVMlHToe5enBANK-DnRVGSO7pCkpU/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Introduction to Data Visualization with Fusion Tables. &lt;em&gt;UTSC Undergraduate Studies Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 - Project Collaboration in Digital Scholarship. &lt;em&gt;Diasporic Foodways.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Digital Toolkit: Storytelling and Filmmaking for Video II. &lt;em&gt;UTSC Undergraduate Studies Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - To Code or Not to Code?. &lt;em&gt;Special Libraries Association Article Club.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Visualizing Geolocated Data with MapsEngine and Leaflet. &lt;em&gt;Digital Pedagogy Institute.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Collaboration &amp;amp; Tools for Digital Food Mapping. &lt;em&gt;City Food Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Introduction to Islandora &amp;amp; the Doris McCarthy fonds. &lt;em&gt;Berkshire Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Information Use &amp;amp; Reuse: Open Source App Development in Libraries. &lt;em&gt;TRY Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Intranets and Interaction Design. &lt;em&gt;University of Toronto iSchool Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - Information Use &amp;amp; Reuse: Open Source App Development in Libraries. &lt;em&gt;OLA Superconference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2013 - Closing the Gender Gap: A working analysis of Harvard Business School’s recent policy shift. &lt;em&gt;University of Toronto iSchool Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2013 - Historical Scarborough – Then and Now. &lt;em&gt;The Scarborough Historical Mapping Project, University of Toronto iSchool.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1rgBY98vmURyqsMUP0yJFCEN8ri5_n2Zkypm4aE5CDFE/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012 - Marketing in Libraries. &lt;em&gt;University of Toronto iSchool Forum.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012 - Making Maps with MapsEngine and Leaflet. &lt;em&gt;TRY Conference.&lt;/em&gt; Toronto, Canada. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fEaOAjp0SqUC8esVlfXDPgxCxcwuYdfLQD_gWE_s6D8/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;access slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/publications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/publications/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last updated in 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024 - Sustainable Semantics for Sustainable Research Data. &lt;em&gt;SemDH@ESWC 2024.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3724/short3.pdf"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 - Position Statements → Collections as Data: State of the field and future directions. &lt;em&gt;Collections as Data: State of the field and future directions.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://zenodo.org/records/7897735"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Tracing Innovation with Representation Learning in the Sphaera Corpus. &lt;em&gt;6th Graphs and Networks in the Humanities Conference.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://graphentechnologien.hypotheses.org/files/2022/01/Tracing_Innovation_with_Representation_Learning_in_the_textit_etc-Pham.pdf"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - The Network of Early Modern Printers and Its Impact on the Spread of Scientific Knowledge: Automatic Detection of Awareness Relations. &lt;em&gt;Histories.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/histories2040033"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 - Just Because We Can Doesn’t Mean We Should: On Knowing and Protecting Data Produced by the Jewish Consumptives’ Relief Society. &lt;em&gt;Humanist Studies &amp;amp; the Digital Age 7.1.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.5399/uo/hsda/7.1.8"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - A Vertical Cooperation Model to Manage Digital Collections and Institutional Resources. &lt;em&gt;MDPI Publications 8, 23.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2304-6775/8/2/23"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - Building a Library Search Infrastructure with Elasticsearch. &lt;em&gt;code4lib journal.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://journal.code4lib.org/articles/15203"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Mapping with Python and Leaflet. &lt;em&gt;Programming Historian.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://programminghistorian.org/en/lessons/mapping-with-python-leaflet"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Annotation-based Enrichment of Digital Objects Using Open-source Frameworks. &lt;em&gt;code4lib journal.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://journal.code4lib.org/articles/12582"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 - Supporting Oral Histories in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;code4lib journal.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://journal.code4lib.org/articles/12176"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Introduction to Web Scraping. &lt;em&gt;Library Carpentry.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://librarycarpentry.org/lc-webscraping/02-xpath/index.html"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - Building Digital Collections: Three Case Studies in Islandora. &lt;em&gt;Open Shelf Magazine.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://open-shelf.ca/160501-using-islandora/"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - The Scarborough Historical GIS Mapping Project. &lt;em&gt;ACMLA Bulletin 148.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://dai.mun.ca/PDFs/acmla/Number148NewsletterAssociationofCanadianMapLibraries.pdf"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Videos</title><link>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/videos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/videos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some embarrassing talks that i could find of myself online&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Awards</title><link>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/awards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kimpham54.github.io/cv/awards/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 - Mellon Foundation for Collections as Data: Part to Whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 - University of Toronto Libraries STAR Award for Innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 - University of Toronto Gordon Cressy Leadership Award&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>